

CONTACT ME

- +91 9176204928
- devanand151101@gamil.com
- in LinkedIn
- □ Portfolio Site
- No.57/61, Dharmapuram Main Road, T.Nagar, Ch-17,TN, India

EDUCATION

High School

Ramakrishna Mission Matriculation Higher Secondary School

SSLC - 84.4%, HSC - 72%

Bachelor of Engineering CSE

Vel Tech Multi Tech Dr. Rangarajan Dr. Sakunthala Engineering College

First Class with Distinction - CGPA 9.09

SKILLS

Graphic and Web Design	95%
Web Development	90%
Hardwork	90%
Photography and Editing	80%
Analytical Thinking	85%

DEVANAND MATHIVANAN

Full Stack Developer

ABOUT ME

I'm Devanand, a passionate and accomplished computer science engineer with a strong background in full stack web development, AI, ML, UI/UX designing, gaming, ethical hacking, and cyber security. With my extensive knowledge and skills in these areas, I strive to push the boundaries of technology and create immersive digital experiences. As an Oracle Certified Associate, I possess the expertise to tackle complex challenges head-on. My programming arsenal includes Python, Java, JavaScript, and more. Join me on this exciting journey as we transform ideas into reality, one line of code at a time.

OBJECTIVE

Get a good job where I can gain a lot of guidance and knowledge from more experienced professionals from the IT field, to build a lot of connections with very talented people and to learn a lot about emerging technologies.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

FULL STACK DEVELOPEMENT

FRONTEND:

- React.js
- Django
- Tailwind CSS
- Bootstrap
- · Sass,etc.
- BACKEND:
- Express.js Node.js
- Springboot
- REST APIs
- SQL/NoSQL

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGE

- Java
- Python
- Php
- C++
- C# (C Sharp)

HOBBIES

"Embracing life's richness through hobbies that inspire and rejuvenate, I find joy in every moment."

- Painting
- Video Games
- Football
- Origami
- · Reading, etc.



DEVANAND

MATHIVANAN

Full Stack Developer

ABOUT

I'm Devanand, a versatile computer science engineer experienced in full stack web development, A.I., M.L., UI/UX design, Video gaming, ethical hacking, and cyber security. With expertise in Python, Java, C, C++ and more, I am dedicated to shaping innovative digital experiences and overcoming complex challenges.

CONTACT ME

- +91 9176204928
- devanand151101@gamil.com
- in LinkedIn
- □ Portfolio Site
- No.57/61, Dharmapuram Main Road, T.Nagar, Ch-17,TN, India

LINKS

https://github.com/Deva0813

https://www.linkedin.com/in/devanand-m-9a22351b3/

EXPERIENCE

Digital Engineer Intern

Jan 2023 - April 2023

Virtusa Consulting Services Pvt Ltd,

TECH: React.js, Springboot, Java, REST API, Git

Virtual Internship on OpenCV

Feb 2022 - Mar 2022

National Small Industries Corp. Ltd.

TECH: Python, Jupyter Notebook, OpenCV

Cybersecurity Virtual Internship Program

Jan 2022 - Feb 2022

Forage - SAP

TECH: Linux, Phishing, Spam Attacks, etc.

PROJECTS

Real time Sign Language Translator Virtual Camera

TECH STACK: AI/ML, Python, Flask framework, Yolov5, Open CV, Pytorch **DESCRIPTION:** This program is developed to solve the communication barrier between Normal person and specially abled using Deep learning. This Application can be used as virtual camera in any video conference application.

Keep Notes App

TECH STACK: React.js, Next.js, MongoDB, Tailwind CSS, Node.js

DESCRIPTION: Introducing a straightforward notes app created using React.js, Next.js, MongoDB, and Tailwind CSS, providing a user-friendly solution for basic note-taking tasks.

• IAS Academy Portal

TECH STACK: React.js, Node.js, Java, Springboot, REST APIs

DESCRIPTION: This web app serves as an IAS academy portal, managing student details and their enrolled courses using React.js for the user interface and Spring Boot with Maven for the backend.

Sign Language Translator - Action Detection

TECH STACK: Python, Tensorflow, Deep Learning, OpenCV, LSTM

DESCRIPTION: This program is developed to translate the sign language to readable text which uses Deep Learning and Computer vision based on the actions of the user.

• Facebook Data Analysis

TECH STACK: Java, Big Data, Hadoop

DESCRIPTION: Using Hadoop and Java, this project analyzes vast Facebook datasets to uncover insights driving better decisions and user engagement.



DEVANAND

MATHIVANAN

Full Stack Developer

ABOUT

I'm Devanand, a versatile computer science engineer experienced in full stack web development, A.I., M.L., UI/UX design, Video gaming, ethical hacking, and cyber security. With expertise in Python, Java, C, C++ and more, I am dedicated to shaping innovative digital experiences and overcoming complex challenges.

CONTACT ME

- +91 9176204928
- devanand151101@gamil.com
- in LinkedIn
- □ Portfolio Site
- No.57/61, Dharmapuram Main Road, T.Nagar, Ch-17,TN, India

LINKS



https://github.com/Deva0813



https://www.linkedin.com/in/devanand-m-9a22351b3/

CERTIFICATIONS

Oracle Certified JAVA Associate

Mar 2023

Oracle Learning

TECH: Java Core, Java SE 8, Java Advanced

Project on Real-Time Communication System Powered by Al for Specially Abled

Feb 2023

IBM Nalayathiran - ICT Academy

TECH: Ethical Hacking, Cyber Sec, Cyber Attcaks, etc.

The Complete 2023 Web Development Bootcamp

Jan 2022

Udemy

TECH: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React.js, Express.js, etc. (Full Stack)

The Complete Python Pro Bootcamp for 2023

Oct 2022

Udemy

TECH: Python, Python Libraries, Flask, Web Development using Python

Practical Ethical Hacking

Dec 2020

TCM Security

TECH: Ethical Hacking, Cyber Sec, Cyber Attcaks, etc.